A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Letter to Joe Slater: progress report on trip to Europe re: developing and disseminating information concerning the results of differing policies directed towards common problems (Reports 010726), 1963; Chamberlain, Neil W. (Box 432)
  Policy sciences -- Europe; Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development
- Letter to Joe Slater re recommendations for educational television (Reports 010727), undated; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976 (Box 432)
  Television in education; Television -- Educational
- Excellence and the good life: a proposal on educational television (Reports 010728), 1963; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976 (Box 432)
- ESL in the IA area (Reports 010729), 1963; Cullen, Matthew (Box 432)
- Atlantic College (Reports 010730), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 432)
  Education, Higher -- Internationalism; Atlantic College
- Trip to Singapore, New Zealand, Australia and Japan, November 28-December 21, 1967 (Reports 010731), 1968; Gant, George F. (Box 432)
  Memo to Eugene S. Staples, dated January 15, 1968.
- Brief description and list of prior Ford Foundation grants in support of activities in the Atlantic area (1950-1963) (Reports 010732) (Box 432)
  Ford Foundation -- Endowments -- Europe
- European management education (Reports 010733), 1966; Catalano, Richard M. (Box 432)
  Education -- Management -- Europe
- Report of inquiry into ways the Ford Foundation can appropriately assist the United Nations adaptation to changing needs and opportunities (Reports 010734), 1962; Finkelstein, Lawrence S. (Box 432)
  58 p. -- 28 cm.
  International agencies; International relations; International organization; Humanitarianism; United Nations
- International Affairs Program: discussion paper concerning proposed Arms Control Analyses Group in Washington, D.C (Reports 010735), 1960 (Box 432)
  Arms control
- Memorandum for Shepard Stone on European studies and the Atlantic community (Reports 010736), 1962; Moore, Ben T. (Box 433)
  Foreign study -- United States; Area studies -- United States; International relations; CSIS
- Thoughts on strategy for advancing Atlantic partnership (Reports 010737), 1963; Nielsen, Waldemar A. (Box 433)
  International agencies; NATO (Group)
- East European activities of IA program, Septemer (Reports 010738), 1961; Nielsen, Waldemar A. (Box 433)
  Endowments -- Europe, Eastern -- Evaluation; International relations
- European business schools (Reports 010739), 1957; Nielsen, Waldemar A. (Box 433)
  Education -- Europe; Business education -- Europe
- A proposal for an international educational development program (Reports 010740), 1959; Nielsen, Waldemar A. (Box 433)
  Education -- International development program; Acculturation
- Mass media activities of the IA program (Reports 010741), 1961; Nielsen, Waldemar A. (Box 433)
  Media -- International news; Communication
- United States government support of research in foreign countries (Reports 010742), 1960; Pearson, Paul B., 1905- (Box 433)
  Science -- Research grants; Technology -- Research grants
- My trip to Japan July 5 - August 4, 1962 (Reports 010743), Passin, Herbert (Box 433)
  Technical assistance -- Japan; Endowments -- Japan -- Evaluation; International relations
- The International Economic Association meetings (Reports 010744), 1965; Pendleton, William C. (Box 433)
  International relations -- Economic aspects
- Long-range organizational and personnel program for the Atlantic community affairs (Reports 010745), 1962; Schaetzel, Robert (Box 433)
  Foreign affairs -- United States
- The Institute of International Education (Reports 010746), 1965; Stone, Shepard (Box 433)
  International education; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.)
- Atlantic Institute (Reports 010747), 1966; Beugel, Ernst Hans van der, 1918-2004 (Box 433)
  [5] p. -- 28 cm.
  Educational change; Educational planning; Atlantic Institute
- A summary evaluation and recommendation: Arms control research and information (Reports 010748), 1964; Teeple, John B., 1928- (Box 433)
- The Second International Conference of Broadcasting Organizations on Sound and Television School Broadcasting: Tokyo, April 9-15 (Reports 010749), 1964; White, Stephen, 1945-; International Conference of Broadcasting Organizations on Sound and Television School Broadcasting ( 2nd: 1964 April 9-15, Tokyo) (Box 433)
  International Affairs;Education
  International Conference of Broadcasting Organizations on Sound and Television School Broadcasting ( 2nd: 1964 April 9-15, Tokyo)
  Television in education -- International -- Congresses; Communication -- Educational broadcasting -- Congresses
- Arms control and disarmament research (Reports 010750), 1963; Stevenson, Eric (Box 433)
  Arms control; Disarmament
- International health activities (Reports 010751), 1958; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 433)
  4 p. + appendices.
  Health -- International activities
- Preliminary report of J.E. Slater on Foundation Yugoslav Program (Reports 010752), 1960; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 433)
  International Affairs Program [IA];International Affairs
  Education, Higher -- Exchange Program
- Atlantic Foundation (Reports 010753), 1960; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 433)
  International relations; Atlantic Foundation; CSIS
- Ethnomusicology in Indonesia and the Philippines: report to the Ford Foundation on a three-week lecture tour (Reports 010754), 1986; Becker, Judith, 1932- (Box 433)
  Ethnomusicology; Music -- Culture
- Summary tables FY 1981 and comparisons with earlier years (Reports 010755), 1982 (Box 433)
  Budget -- International Division; International Division
- A look at the MAT model of teacher education and its graduates: lessons for today (Reports 010756), 1985; Coley, Richard J. (Box 433)
  34 p. + appendices.
  Education, Higher; Education; MAT.
- Notes used by WML in discussion at Beirut on potential cultural activities in OD countries, Jan. (Reports 010757), 1967; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 433)
  Culture
- An evaluation of energy conservation programs serving low income neighborhoods: overcoming the barriers: Residential Conservation Project (Reports 010758), 1985; Technical Development Corporation (Box 433)
  84-420;08300202
  187 p. -- 28 cm.
  Housing -- United States; Energy conservation -- United States; Community development -- United States; Poor -- United States -- Energy assistance
- Nutrition in developing countries and the role of international agencies: in search of a vision (Reports 010759), 1985; Chen, Lincoln C. (Box 433)
  Nutrition
- Employment and income generation (Reports 010760), 1984 (Box 433)
  Selected reading material for a Ford Foundation staff meeting. Materials in this package have been selected to provide a fairly comprehensive presentation of the concepts, issues, projects, techniques and lessons learned in the arena of employment and inc
  Developing Countries Program;Rural Poverty and Resources;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Employment (Economic theory); Income generation; Poor -- Developing countries
- Cultural opportunities in Asia (Reports 010761), 1968; LaMontagne, Ray (Box 433)
  Assimilation (Sociology) -- Asia
- Notes on European trip (Reports 010762), 1957; Gordon, Kermit, 1916-1976 (Box 433)
  48 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Economics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Europe; Central planning -- Europe; Economic development -- Europe
- Foreign investment in the Atlantic area (Reports 010763), 1965; Könz, Peider (Box 433)
  Investments, Foreign -- Europe
- Discussion on OECD Centre for Educational Innovation (Reports 010764), 1966; Meade, Edward J., Jr. (Box 433)
  Education and Research/Public Education;International Affairs
  Education -- Developing countries; Educational planning -- Developing countries
- OECD Conference on Center for Education Innovation (Reports 010765), 1966; Meade, Edward J., Jr. (Box 433)
  various pagings
  Education -- Research; Educational planning -- Developing countries
- Japan (Reports 010766), 1964; Passin, Herbert (Box 433)
- Socio-cultural factors in Japan's perception of her international role (Reports 010767), 1966; Passin, Herbert (Box 433)
  57 leaves -- 28 cm.
  International relations -- Social aspects
- IA International Affairs activities in Japan (Reports 010768), 1966; Nasu, Kiyoshi, 1916- (Box 433)
  Memo to Mr. Stone and Mr. Slater, dated August 23, 1966.
  Technical assistance -- Japan; Endowments -- Japan -- Evaluation
- Background materials on IA International Affairs activities in Japan (Reports 010769), 1966; Stone, Shepard (Box 433)
  6 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
- Report on visit to the Atlantic College (Reports 010770), 1966; Huntley, James Robert (Box 433)
  Education; Atlantic College
- Cleveland World Affairs Council (Reports 010771), 1965; Huntley, James Robert (Box 434)
  International relations -- Education; World affairs -- Citizen education; Education -- International cooperation
- Summary of findings: World Affairs Councils and related bodies in Los Angeles, San Francisco, Portland, Seattle, and Hawaii (Reports 010772), 1965; Huntley, James Robert (Box 434)
  Includes individual reports from councils and related bodies in all of the above cities.
- A world affairs education career service? (Reports 010773), 1966; Huntley, James Robert (Box 434)
  International relations -- Education; International relations -- Citizen education; Education -- International cooperation
- Personnel for world affairs education: Results of meeting March 16 (Reports 010774), 1966; Huntley, James Robert (Box 434)
  International relations -- Education; International relations -- Citizen education; Education -- Foreign affairs
- World affairs education: Where do we go from here? (Reports 010775), 1966; Huntley, James Robert (Box 434)
- Administration of the appropriation for grants to world affairs councils for support of community world affairs programs (Reports 010776), 1965; Nichols, Calvin J. (Box 434)
- Notes concerning individual world affairs councils (Reports 010777), 1965; Nichols, Calvin J. (Box 434)
- Requests for grants from the National Council of Women and the International Council of Women (Reports 010778), 1966; McVicker, Charles P. (Box 434)
  Women's rights
- Visit to INSEAD European Institute of Business Administration, Paris, May 28 (Reports 010779), 1966; Catalano, Richard M. (Box 434)
  Industrial management -- Europe
- Ivory Coast (Reports 010780), 1963; Heaps, David (Box 434)
  Includes Agricultural project, Ivory Coast. March 1963. 2 p.
  Côte d'Ivoire; Africa, West
- United Nations Institute for Training and Research (Reports 010781), 1964; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 434)
  International officials and employees -- Training of; International agencies; International relations; United Nations Institute for Training and Research
- International cultural exchange memo in three parts -- 1, Cultural exchange in the United States -- 2, Ford Foundation support of cultural exchange -- 3, Soviet Union's cultural exchange program (Reports 010782), 1956; McKeever, Porter (Box 434)
  Exchange of persons programs
- A program of philanthropic support of cultural affairs through institutions in the humanities and creative arts (Reports 010783), 1955; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 434)
  Discussion paper about the possibility that the foundation will undertake a program in the field of cultural affairs.
  Arts; Culture; Philanthropy
- The arts and humanities: American Assembly, International Educational and Cultural Exchange (Reports 010784), 1962; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913-; Hooker, Gertrude (Box 434)
  69 p.
  Arts -- United States; Exchange of persons programs
- Talk with Isaac Stern (Reports 010785), 1957; D'Arms, Edward F. (Box 434)
  Music; Musicians
- International Affairs in the field of international cultural exchange (Reports 010786), 1957; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 434)
  Exchange of persons programs; International relations
- The role of International Affairs Program in international cultural activities (Reports 010787), 1957; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 434)
- Paper on international cultural activities, Oct. (Reports 010788), 1957; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 434)
  Comment on paper #010494.
  International Affairs;Humanities and the Arts
  Culture; Philanthropy
- International cultural activities (Reports 010789), 1958; Stone, Shepard; Nielsen, Waldemar A.; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 434)
- Proposed project for international cultural cooperation and exchange (FY - 1964) (Reports 010790), 1963 (Box 434)
- Observations on Paul Doty's paper, "Observations on Japanese science" (Reports 010791), 1962; Passin, Herbert (Box 434)
  Paul Doty's paper is #010791.
  Science -- Japan
- Scientific progress and foreign policy: notes on conversations held in November-December 1962 and (Reports 010792), 1963; Reber, Samuel (Box 434)
  6 p. + attachment.
  International relations -- Science
- International Centre for Theoretical Physics: Trieste (Reports 010793), 1966; Stone, Shepard (Box 434)
  Physical sciences; Science -- International cooperation
- Conference on international cooperation in television (Reports 010794), 1966; Dressner, Howard R. (Box 434)
  International Affairs;OS
  Television -- International cooperation; Communication -- International broadcasting
- A report on N.E.T. public affairs programs (Reports 010795), 1965; Brucker, Herbert, 1898-1977 (Box 434)
  Special Programs
  Journalism -- National Educational Television; Television in education -- Public services
- International Broadcast Institute (Reports 010796), 1966; Stone, Shepard (Box 434)
  Television -- International relations; Communication -- International broadcasting
- Memorandum to Howard Dressner re thoughts on educational television (Reports 010800), 1965; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976 (Box 434)
  Office of the Secretary;Special Programs
  Television in education; Ford Foundation. Special Programs
- Memorandum to Joe Slater reporting reaction to IBI International Broadcast Institute (Reports 010801), 1966; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976 (Box 434)
  Communication; International broadcasting
- Discussion with David Webster of the BBC re European television (Reports 010802), 1965; Slater, Joseph E. (Box 434)
  Television -- Europe; Communication -- International cooperation
- Recent trip to Italy (Reports 010803), 1966; LaPalombara, Joseph, 1925- (Box 434)
  Television -- Foreign affairs -- Italy
- Proposed international study of public affairs television broadcasting (Reports 010804), 1965; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976 (Box 434)
  Television -- Public services; Communication -- International broadcasting
- Memorandum on an independent school fund: general comments (Reports 010805), 1955; Bender, W. J. (Box 434)
  Private schools
- Report on European trip (mental health) (Reports 010806), 1955; Berelson, Bernard, 1912-1979 (Box 434)
  Program planning
- A study of the graduate school in the United States (Reports 010807), 1957; Berelson, Bernard, 1912-1979 (Box 434)
  Program planning; Education, Higher
- The Fund for Adult Education: a statement concerning its objectives, its past activities and its future needs, Mar. (Reports 010808), 1954; Brown, Dyke (Box 434)
  [15] p.
- Notes on future support to Fund for Adult Education, March 24 (Reports 010809), 1954; Brown, Dyke (Box 434)
  Adult education -- United States; Television in education -- United States; Fund for Adult Education (U.S.)
- Memorandum on Administrative Internship Program (Reports 010810), 1955; Burdine, J. Alton (John Alton), 1905- (Box 434)
  Internship programs
- A study of "Perspectives" in England, France, Germany and Italy (Reports 010811), 1954; Burkhardt, Frederick, 1912-2007 (Box 434)
  76 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Intellectual cooperation; Perspectives (Journal)
- A statement to the officers and trustees of the Ford Foundation concerning a plan for the support by the Foundation of a program to promote the public study and discussion of the disarmament problem (Reports 010812), 1954; Clark, Grenville, 1882-1967 (Box 434)
  Outlines a plan whereby the Foundation could effectively aid the study and discussion throughout the United States of the problems of world disarmament and to state the reasons why the Foundation's support of such a program would be an important contribut
- Background for disarmament discussion (Reports 010813), 1954; Clark, Grenville, 1882-1967 (Box 434)
  This paper attempts to provide background useful to an understanding of the problem of disarmament.
  Disarmament; Arms control
- Projection by percentages for use of funds to advance liberal adult education in the U.S.A. through December 31, 1961: Preliminary staff suggestions (Reports 010814), 1955; Fletcher, C. Scott (Cyril Scott), 1904-1991 (Box 435)
  Adult education
- Chicago Law School study of the Jury Project Series (Reports 010815), 1955 (Box 435)
  Jury -- United States; Jurors -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; University of Chicago. Law School
- Notes on previous Foundation experience with fluid grants (Reports 010816), 1950 (Box 435)
  Endowments -- Finance; Ford Foundation. President
- Press reaction to the report of the Reece Committee, January 4 (Reports 010817), 1955 (Box 435)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Press coverage; Philanthropy -- United States -- Press coverage; Reece Committee; United States. Congress. House. Special Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations
- Report on "A program in behavioral science research" (Reports 010818), 1951 (Box 435)
  4 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Interpersonal relations -- Research; Psychology -- Research; Social sciences -- Research; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- A review of some new techniques for the handling of information as they may be related to the acquisition and functioning of a modern library (Reports 010819), undated (Box 435)
  Library administration
- Statement to the Special Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations (Reports 010820), 1954; Gaither, H. Rowan (Horace Rowan), 1909-1961 (Box 435)
  [29] p. -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Finance; United States. Congress (83rd: 1953-1954); American Bar Association. Robinson-Patman Act Committee
- Program review and projection: Behavioral Sciences Division (Reports 010821), 1953 (Box 435)
  Educational evaluation
- Advisory Group on Economics and Behavioral Sciences report (Reports 010822), 1953 (Box 435)
- Working paper for meeting of Advisory Group on Mental Health Program (Reports 010823), 1955 (Box 435)
  Mental health
- The Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Reports 010824), 1952 (Box 435)
  Social sciences; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, Calif.)
- Education: development as a Foundation-administered program (Reports 010825), 1956 (Box 435)
  Education; Ford Foundation. Program Area Four.
- Statement of H. Rowan Gaither, Jr. president and trustee to the Special Committee to Investigate Tax Exempt Foundations, July 16 (Reports 010826), 1954; Gaither, H. Rowan (Horace Rowan), 1909-1961 (Box 435)
  44 p. + supplement -- 28 cm
- Hospital program: six months progress report June 15 (Reports 010827), 1956 (Box 435)
  Hospitals -- United States; Medical care -- United States
- The Fund for the Republic (Reports 010828), 1954 (Box 435)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Finance; United States. Congress (83rd: 1953-1954); Fund for the Republic; Reece Committee
- History of the Fund for the Advancement of Education (Reports 010829), 1954 (Box 435)
  60 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Educational assistance -- United States; Education -- Social aspects -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Fund for the Advancement of Education (U.S.)
- Summary report on the status of follow-up activities of the New York office (Reports 010830), 1952; Gladieux, Bernard L. (Bernard Louis), 1907-1997 (Box 435)
  Memorandum to Joseph M. McDaniel.
  Management -- Ford Foundation
- Statement of Paul G. Hoffman, Chairman of the Board, The Fund for the Republic (Reports 010831), 1954; Hoffman, Paul G. (Box 435)
  6 p. -- 28c m.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Finance; Fund for the Republic; United States. Congress (83rd: 1953-1954); Reece Committee
- Statement by Bernard L. Gladieux of the Ford Foundation (Reports 010832), 1954; Gladieux, Bernard L. (Bernard Louis), 1907-1997 (Box 435)
  Purpose of statement was to place on record the facts concerning allegations made about Gladieux by Congressman Carroll Reece of Tennessee in July 1953 as part of a prepared statement to the House of Representatives supporting H.R. 217 which authorized th
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Reece Committee
- Progress report: survey of problems of the handicapped (Reports 010833), 1956; Harkavy, Oscar (Box 435)
  People with disabilities
- The 5.1 Program Behavioral Sciences (Reports 010834), 1951; Herring, Pendleton (Box 435)
  Social sciences -- Research
- Submission by Henry T. Heald, President, the Ford Foundation to the Select Committee on Government Research (Reports 010835), 1963; Heald, Henry T. (Henry Townley) (Box 435)
  Research -- Government and education; Elliot Committee.
- Plans for an appraisal of the present status of educational television in the United States (Reports 010836), 1956; Hull, Richard B.; National Educational Television and Radio Center (Box 435)
  Television in education; National Educational Television and Radio Center
- Report to the Citizen's Group regarding plans for a television development center to be supported by the Ford Foundation (Reports 010837), 1954; Lazarsfeld, Paul F., 1901-1976; Citizens Group on Television (Box 435)
  Television in education; Citizens Group on Television
- The Foundation's relations with intermediaries (Reports 010838), 1954; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 435)
- Handling of forthcoming request for continued support of The Educational Television and Radio Center at Ann Arbor (Reports 010839), 1955; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 435)
- Interview with Dr. T.E. Blackwell, Vice Chancellor and Treasurer of Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri (Reports 010840), 1956; MacKaye, Milton, 1901-1979 (Box 435)
  Universities and colleges; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.)
- Report on plant needs in private colleges and universities (Reports 010841), 1957; MacKaye, Milton, 1901-1979 (Box 435)
  55 p. + appendices.
  College buildings
- Public relations (Reports 010842), 1955; McKeever, Porter (Box 436)
  Public relations
- Area IV overview (Reports 010843), undated; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
- College student loans (Reports 010844), undated; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
  Memorandum to Henry T. Heald.
  [10] p.
  Student aid; Student loans; Universities and colleges
- Comments on possible Ford Foundation program in medicine and health (Reports 010845), 1959; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
  Memo to Mr. Henry T. Heald.
- Concerning the Ford Foundation (Reports 010846), 1953; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
  Management -- Ford Foundation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations
- Foundation flexibility (Reports 010847), 1958; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
- Maximizing effectiveness of Ford Foundation grants (Reports 010848), 1949; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
  Grant making; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations
- Medical education (Reports 010849), 1955; McPeak, William Wallace (Box 436)
  Medical education; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations